# 大家好 上次來兄弟家釣魚 看到他這個烤爐啊
Hi everyone. Last time we came fishing at our buddy's place and we saw this thing, his oven.
# 我們把它抬回去 反正兄弟也用不上
We're taking it back. My buddy doesn't use it anyway.
# 拿回去給竹鼠看一下
Let's take it back and show it to the bamboo rats.
# 下面可以扶穩
You can hold the bottom.
# 這裡還有個底座
Here's also a base.
# 要兩個人枱
It needs both of us.
# 這個也把它抱回家
And this one too.
# 放在那旁邊
Put it next to it.
# 先把這個炭先燒一下
Let me light the charcoal first.
# 我也不知道烤甚麼好
I have no ideas what to roast.
# 等一下我看到 看到甚麼我就烤甚麼
I'll simply roast whatever, whatever comes into my sight.
# 不是吃的 走開走開走開
It's not food! Go 'way, go 'way, go 'way!
# 你們又不要的
You won't want it.
# 炭你們要嗎 要嗎 要嗎 舔啊
You want charcoal? Do you? Do you? Lick it!
# 真是的
Crazy!
# 我先到這裡把這個炭燒著來
I'm using it to light the charcoal first.
# 我把這個火引一下 引到這邊來
Let me bring the fire, bring the fire here.
# 這樣就可以把這個炭點著
Then the charcoal can be lighted.
# 剛好這個炭沒那麼快燒起來
The charcoal may take a while.
# 我去抓只兄弟家的雞來烤一下
Let me catch a chicken from my buddy to have something to roast.
# 就在前面
It's right in the front.
# 你看 把它刮毛
Look! It's dehaired.
# 不胖也不瘦 剛剛好
It's not too fat, not too skinny. Perfect!
# 屁股那麼大
What a large butt!
# 把這個
Let me...
# 把這個肚子開了 把這個內臟拿掉
cut its belly open and remove the guts.
# 好多油啊 這個
There's a lot of fat.
# 還會叫
It's still cackling.
# 把這個先
Let me first,
# 割幾刀
slice a few times,
# 讓它醃一下
and marinate it for a while.
# 不然沒味
It's tasteless otherwise.
# 聽說這個屁股會有點 有點味道
They told me that the butt might, might smell a bit awkward.
# 我都還沒吃過
I've never tried before.
# 不吃了 給你們吃
Give it to you guys. I don't want it.
# 可以 就這樣掛在這裡
Alright! So it can be hung inside the oven.
# 是不是就這樣掛的
Am I right?
# 慢慢烤
Roast slowly
# 先把它醃一下
Let me marinate it first.
# 拍點生薑醃下去先
Smash some ginger first.
# 我裡面再放點料子下去
I'll then put some other seasonings.
# 加點鹽
Put some salt.
# 這個鹽要
The salt needs to be,
# 撒均勻
evenly sprinkled.
# 里面也搞一勺
A spoonful inside as well
# 撒在它傷口上
Rub into its wound.
# 料酒
Cooking wine
# 醬油
Soy sauce
# 油
Oil
# 好啦
Alright!
# 還是要給他按按摩
I still need to give it a massage,
# 更入味哦
to make it more flavourful.
# 要再這樣 這樣醃個半個小時才行哦
Then we need to, we need to marinate for half an hour.
# 不然味道沒有融入到裡面去
Otherwise the flavour cannot be fully absorbed.
# 請勿触摸 小心燙手 (非對白)
DO NOT TOUCH
CAUTION! VERY HOT
# 你看 這個兩百多度哦
Look! It's higher than 200 degrees.
# 可以 我把那個雞搞過來
Alright! I'll fetch the chicken.
# 勾 勾往這裡 勾到它腳這一塊
Hook, hook it here, here on the foot.
# 哎呦 戳我一下
Ayo! I stabbed myself.
# 太冷啦
It's too cold.
# 誒呀
Eeya!
# 剛剛好
Perfect!
# 剛好放在這裡勾著
It can be hung right here.
# 好慘啊
Poor chicken!
# 蓋子蓋起來
Put on the lid.
# 蓋著
Cover it.
# 讓它燒一燒
Let it roast.
# 先把這個放好
Place it back first.
# 哇
Wa!
# 它在冒煙 冒油啦
The smoke, the oils is coming out.
# 看下去都想吃
I already wanna start eating.
# 沒那麼快
It still needs a while.
# 蓋起來 不要它的味道走了
Cover it! Don't let the flavour run away.
# 小心燙手 (非對白)
CAUTION! VERY HOT
# 請勿触摸 小心燙手 (非對白)
DO NOT TOUCH
CAUTION! VERY HOT
# 哇 這個溫度都二百五十度了
Wa! It's already 250 degrees.
# 看一下
Take a look!
# 誒呀 那麼猛的火
Ayo! The fire is so strong!
# 誒呀 好靚哦
Ayo! It's beautiful!
# 你看
Look!
# 那肉都開始有點燒焦啦
The meat is already a bit burnt.
# 可以可以可以
Good, good good!
# 都差不多三百度啦 我看一下
It's almost 300 degrees. Let me have a look.
# 誒呀 可以啦可以啦可以啦
Aya! It's done, it's done, it's done!
# 差點燒掉啦
It's almost burnt.
# 你看 腳都燒焦啦
Look! The feet are already burnt.
# 幸好發現的[SIC]快
I'm just in time.
# 要不然雞都沒得吃了
Otherwise there would be nothing left.
# 你看 這個雞
Look! This chicken,
# 很香哦
smells so good,
# 很漂亮哦
and it's so pretty.
# 去裡面
Let's go inside.
# 果然不錯
It's really not bad.
# 雞腳都脆啦
The chicken feet are crispy.
# 要火燒啦 (註︰我想他是用錯詞吧？)
It's burnt.
# 可以哦 這個爐子很實用的哦
Not bad! The oven is really nice.
# 剛好入味
The flavour is perfect.
# 不老也不嫩 剛剛好
The texture is just right, not too hard, not too soft.
# 把它的雞翅先掰下來
Let me take the chicken wing first.
# 別被狗跳起來吃掉啦
Don't let the dogs jump and get it.
# 好啦 今天的視頻到這裡啦
Alright! The video ends here.
# 不能說話 再說話又掉一塊
I need to stop talking. Otherwise I'm gonna drop another piece.